You must have heard about ICICI Bank
and apart from this, you must have also heard that
ICICI Bank also has a mutual fund
named ICICI Prudential Asset
Management Company i.e. ICICI Prudential
Mutual Fund. ICICI Bank
is one of the largest banks in India and Prudential
PLC, which is a London based company, is
one of the largest insurance and asset management companies in the world. Friends,
in this video we will tell you about the
top three mutual fund schemes of ICICI Prudential Mutual Fund
and will tell you how
these mutual fund schemes have
generated returns in the last few years and will also
tell you how
you can invest in these mutual fund schemes without any paperwork sitting at home.
Hello, I am
Manish Taneja and you are watching Z Funds. Z Funds is
where your investments are right and
easy. Z Funds is where you can do daily
SIP. Yes, when we earn daily, spend daily and
save daily, then why not
invest daily? Download Z Funds app today
and start your daily SIP journey.
Z Funds is where your  Investments are right
and easy IIC Prudential Mutual Fund has a
track record of more than 25 years in fund management and it is the
second largest mutual fund house in India. The
AUM of this mutual fund house means it
manages assets worth Rs 690 thousand crores.
995 lakh investors from India have invested in this mutual fund house.
This
mutual fund house offers more than 120
mutual fund schemes to its
investors. Let us talk about the
top three schemes of the mutual fund house.
After thorough analysis of the z funds,
after observing the market fluctuations and after comparing the
returns of all the schemes and after reviewing their fund
management strategies, the
team of z funds has identified
these three schemes of IIC Potential Mutual Fund.
Value Discovery Fund: This scheme was launched
in August 2004 and since 2004 till date,
this scheme has
given returns at an annual rate of 20.6 to approximately 205 per cent to its AFO
investors. That is, if any
AFO investor has invested in the scheme  If a lump sum
investment of ₹1 lakh had been made, the value of that ₹1 lakh today would have been ₹
1.76 crore. Yes, 1.5 crore. The
benchmark of this scheme is Nifty 500 Total
Return Index and the AUM of the scheme is
3937.6 crore. Yes,
this mutual fund scheme is worth approximately ₹39000 crore.
You can start investing in this mutual fund scheme with
just ₹1,000,000. Yes, you can
also do daily SIP in this mutual fund scheme,
which you can start with ₹1.
Talking about the top holdings of this fund, the
top holdings of this mutual fund scheme
are
reliancelife.com.
Most of the allocation deployed across instruments is in equity.
This is an equity fund and an equity fund
carries equity risk and an
equity mutual fund
also delivers returns of equity as an asset class. Let us
now talk about the
second scheme of ICICI Potential Mutual Fund. The name of this scheme
is ICICI Prudential
Infrastructure Fund. The scheme was launched in August 2005.  It has
given an annual return of 16.18% to its AFO investors but this
scheme has significantly accelerated the pace of its returns in the last few years.
In the last three years, this fund has
given an annual return of 39.2%. If
investors had invested ₹1 lakh in the AFO of this fund, then
today their value of ₹1 lakh would have been
approximately ₹4.36 lakh. The benchmark of the scheme
is SNP BSE India
Infrastructure Total Return Index and
its AUM is approximately 4500 crores.
You can start SIP in this fund as well from ₹1. Yes, at
z funds, you can start your investment in this fund with an SIP of ₹1 per day.
Talking about the top holdings of this fund, the
top holdings of this scheme are
NTPC, Larsen & Toubro, III Bank and
Gujarat Gas. If we look at the asset allocation of this fund,
93.9% of this fund is invested
in equity and approximately 6% is invested in cash.
Yes, the fund managers invest approximately 6% in  But cash
balance is maintained. Keep in mind that this is
a thematic equity fund. Yes, not
only is it an equity fund, it is a thematic
fund, that is, a sector specific fund, which means
this fund also has similar schemes. The
third scheme
we will tell you about in this video is ICICI
Prudential Blue Chip Fund. Launched in May 2008,
this scheme has given returns to its AFO investors at an
annual rate of 15.2%. That is,
if you had invested ₹1 lakh in the AFO of this fund, then
today the value of that ₹1.81 lakh would have been
approximately ₹1.81 lakh. So the
benchmark of this scheme is Nifty 100 Total
Return Index and the EOM of this fund is
4983, that means the AUM of the scheme is approximately ₹50000 crore.
In this fund also, you
can start your investment with just ₹1000000. Yes, on
Z Funds, you can start your investment in AAA Prudential Blue
Chip Fund with a daily SIP of ₹1000000.  You can
start investing. Talking about the
top holdings of this fund, these
are
Reliance 1. On allocation, this fund
is currently 92.8% in equity, meaning 93% allocation is
in equity, and the fund managers are
maintaining a cash balance of approximately 7%. Keep in mind
that this fund is also a pure equity fund, and
equity market risks are involved in it too.
Friends, these were the
top three
schemes of ICICI Prudential Mutual Fund. To find out how much allocation should you make in these schemes,
whether these schemes are right for your portfolio,
and which mutual fund
schemes can help you achieve your financial goals,
download zFunds today and talk to
your zFunds expert. Let's now look at the annual returns of these three
schemes over the past one, three, and five years.
In this graphic, you can see the annual returns of ICICI Potential Value
Discovery Fund, ICICI Prudential
Infrastructure Fund, and ICICI
Prudential Blue Chip Fund over the past three and five
years.
Investing in these funds is quite easy.
Download z  Funds A and start
your investment journey today through Daily SIP in mutual fund schemes of ICICI Prudential Mutual Fund Z Funds
where your investment is right and easy Much
fund investments are subject to
market risk Read all scheme related
documents carefully